<screen>
    1. Download and install CodeSourcery cross-compiler (for example this one). Also add folder with CodeSourcery to your linux PATH:export PATH=$PATH:&lt;CodeSourcery_folder&gt; 


2. Download and unpack Valgrind 3.6.0;

wget http://valgrind.org/downloads/valgrind-3.6.0.tar.bz2
tar -xjf ./valgrind-3.6.0.tar.bz2
cd ./valgrind-3.6.0 

3. Configure Valgrind (replace &lt;path_to_CodeSourcery&gt; with path to your CodeSourcery):

CC=arm-none-linux-gnueabi-gcc CFLAGS=”-pipe -Os -mtune=cortex-a8 -march=armv7-a -mabi=aapcs-linux -msoft-float -I&lt;path_to_CodeSourcery&gt;/arm-none-linux-gnueabi/libc/usr/include” LDFLAGS=”-L&lt;path_to_CodeSourcery&gt;/arm-none-linux-gnueabi/libc/usr/lib” ./configure –prefix=/opt/valgrind –host=armv7-none-linux-gnueabi –target=arm-none-linux-gnueabi –build=i386-ubuntu-linux 

Please pay attention to the “–prefix=/opt/valgrind” parameter. This is directory where Valgrind will be installed (copied) after “make install” command. This parameter is hard-coded to the Valgrind binaries and you have to copy all Valgrind files from ”/opt/valgrind” on your Ubuntu host to the “/opt/valgrind” folder on your Beagleboard exactly with the same folders/files structure. If Valgrind installed not properly (not to the same place as in “–prefix=” parameter) you’ll see error like that:

# valgrind –version 
valgrind: failed to start tool ‘memcheck’ for platform ‘arm-linux’: No such file or directory

4. Build Valgrind:

make

5. Install Valgrind:

make install

6. Remove unnecessary includes and manual pages:

rm -f -r  /opt/valgrind/include
rm -f -r  /opt/valgrind/share

7. Copy or move next folders from your host to the Beagleboard-xM (you don’t need these binaries on your host any more):

(HOST)                 (BEAGLEBOARD)
/opt/valgrind/bin/* -&gt; /opt/valgrind/bin/*
/opt/valgrind/lib/* -&gt; /opt/valgrind/lib/* 

8. Add Valgrind installation folder to the PATH on your Beagleboard-xM:

PATH=$PATH:/opt/valgrind/bin

9. Make sure everything works.

(!) Please note that you have to use non-stripped standard C/C++ libraries on your Beagleboard-xM or you’ll see errors like that:

# valgrind –leak-check=yes ./test
==125== Memcheck, a memory error detector
==125== Copyright (C) 2002-2010, and GNU GPL’d, by Julian Seward et al.
==125== Using Valgrind-3.6.0 and LibVEX; rerun with -h for copyright info
==125== Command: /home/default/test/test
==125== 

valgrind: Fatal error at startup: a function redirection
valgrind: which is mandatory for this platform-tool combination
valgrind: cannot be set up. Details of the redirection are:
valgrind: 
valgrind: A must-be-redirected function
valgrind: whose name matches the pattern: memcpy
valgrind: in an object with soname matching: ld-linux.so.3
valgrind: was not found whilst processing
valgrind: symbols from the object with soname: ld-linux.so.3ns for this platform.
valgrind: 
valgrind: Cannot continue — exiting now. Sorry.
</screen>
